Connor Joseph Ludwig Staff Software Engineer

Phone: 712-830-6202
Address: Des Moines, IA, US
Email: cjlludwig@gmail.com

Website: https://cjlludwig.github.io
Github: https://github.com/cjlludwig

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/connor-ludwig

Staff Software Engineer at John Deere with over 5 years of experience leading teams to deliver positive business results. Launched a recurring revenue system for a Fortune 100 company. Skilled in creating and supporting cloud infrastructure, data science and analytics platforms, and web applications. Routinely masters new technologies to meet project needs. Open to relocating for the right position.

Professional Experience

Backend & Embedded Staff Software Engineer, Deere & Company, Urbandale, IA

9/2022 to Present

- Primary engineer of novel software licensing service enabling \$10 billion in recurring revenue
- Architected a distributed backend web service with IoT system integrations using Amazon Web Services
- Developed data pipeline for digital sales department with 10,000+ users
- Technical lead for team of 10 developers
- Modernized team's engineering best practices and improved delivery velocity by 2x
- Consulted in staffing decision making for organization of 30+ engineers
- Advised 20+ business stakeholders to guide product definition

Backend & Embedded Senior Software Engineer, Deere & Company, Urbandale, IA

9/2021 to 9/2022

- Launched scalable system to support over 100,000 devices annually across product lines
- Engineered core cloud infrastructure for new licensing service to support 1,000s of requests a second
- Established CI/CD processes in team codebases to reduce deployment times by >30%
- Deployed serverless monitoring and logging for over 20 microservices
- Containerized 10+ codebases with Docker to improve team onboarding and deployments
- Spearheaded secure cryptographic processes to protect billions of dollars in company revenue

Fullstack Software Engineer, Deere & Company, Moline, IL

6/2019 to 9/2021

- Managed an enterprise data lake platform fronted with Databricks with 2,000+ customers
- Introduced data governance web app using React & Node.js for over 1,000 datasets of petabyte sizes
- Lead creation of UI/UX development standards to improve code quality and reduce defects
- Automated data discovery within enterprise data platform
- Improved cloud architecture for large-scale data ingest and egress
- Consulted over 100 customers to identify optimal data analytics solutions based on use case

Software Engineer, Deere & Company, Moline, IL

1/2018 to 6/2019

Enhanced wide range of HR applications including SAP and Java apps used by 50,000+ employees

Software Engineer Intern and Part Time Student, Deere & Company, Moline, IL

5/2017 to 8/2017

• Established models for securing cloud data access for department of 2,000+ engineers

Software Engineer Intern, Boston Scientific, Arden Hills, MN

5/2015 and 5/2016

Developed an automated suite of 20+ regression tests for mobile sales app using Selenium

Technical Skills



Relevant Certifications & Experience

- AWS Developer Associate (Certified)
- AWS Solutions Architect Associate (Certified)
- Python for Data Science (Certified)
- Blue River Machine Learning & AI (Certified)
- Well Architected system design
- CI/CD implementation and tools
- REST APIs & API Development
- Linux and Unix environments
- Unit and Integration Testing
- Front and Back-end development

- Databricks and Apache Spark
- Cloud infrastructure and security practices
- Improving availability, latency, & scalability
- Infrastructure-as-code (IAC)
- Terraform, Cloudformation, and AWS SAM
- Distributed systems
- ETL data pipelines
- Version control using Git and Github
- Containerization with Docker
- Agile methodology & ceremonies

Education

Iowa State University, Ames, IA

Bachelor of Science - Cum Laude

Majors: Management Information Systems, Supply Chain Management

Minor: Computer Science

Leadership & Honors

SHPE National Convention Representative & Technical Evaluator ('22)

Deere Embedded Solutions "Exceptional Collaborator Award" ('22)

Deere Chicago Tech MeetUp Representative & Technical Evaluator ('22)

Big 12 Career Fair Representative ('22)

Databricks "Data Team Innovation Award" Winner ('21)

JD Smart Co-Creation DeepRacer Challenge Champion ('20)

New and Experienced Organizational Network (NEON) Chair ('19 - '22)

Bettendorf High School Computer Science Course Mentor

August 2013 to December 2017